# Htet Lwin Kyaw

Ramkhamhaeng 50, Bang Kapi, Bangkok

Ph : 0626364328

Mail: htetlwinkyaw.94@gmail.com

Line : htetlwink

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/htetlwinkyaw



#### **Summary**

I'm seeking a position with a company that will allow me to apply and enhance my skills of being as an Electronic Engineer. I'm experienced in electronic engineering field originally from Myanmar, currently residing in Bangkok. With a background in electronic engineering and previous work experienced at Frontiir about 4 years and 8 months, I bring expertise in Electronic device troubleshooting and Excel Data Management.

### **Experience**

#### **FRONTIIR (Myanmar Net)**

Yangon, Myanmar

Sep 2019 – Apr 2024 (4 yrs 8 mos)



#### Senior Associate RMA Engineer

Frontiir (Myanmar Net)

Yangon, Myanmar

Apr 2023 – Apr 2024(1year)

- -Improved and update Excel sheets to minimize human errors and maintain data consistency.
- -Generated reports detailing device errors, issues, solutions, and team updates for upper management.
- -Developed Python automation scripts to stream line repair and testing processes, increasing efficiency and reducing errors.
- -Collaborated with related teams to share knowledge and resolve device issues efficiently.
- -Handled urgent repair and testing requests for devices to support collaborating teams promptly.
- -Mentored junior engineers to ensure team standards were met.



#### Associate RMA Engineer

Frontiir

Yangon, Myanmar

Nov 2021- Apr 2023(1year6months)

- -Conducted testing and repair procedures for arrange of Ubiquiti wireless devices including IS-M5, Air Fiber, etc... and Frontiir ONU devices.
- -Handled urgent repair or testing requests for devices to support collaborating teams promptly.
- -Managed the RMA process for Frontiir's defective devices.
- -Created schematic diagrams of commonly damaged PCBs to facilitate the creation and ordering of spare components.
- -Developed and formatted a data entry system using Google Spreadsheet to collect and organize data efficiently.

# Assistant RMA Engineer

Frontiir

Yangon, Myanmar

Sep 2019 - Nov 2021(2years3months)

- -Tested wireless point-to-point devices, including Ubiquiti products such as NBE M5-19, NBE M5-16, IS M5, IS-5AC, IS-M5, Air Gateway, and Air Fiber units.
- -Conducted thorough assessments to ensure devices were in optimal condition for reuse or recovery.
- -Identified defective devices and determined if they were under warranty coverage and Initiated and managed the Ubiquiti RMA process for devices within the warranty period.
- -Fixed and improved Ruckus AP Units to keep them running smoothly.
- -Worked on testing and repairing PWM solar controllers.

#### **Internship Trainee**

Asia General Electric Co., Ltd

Jun 2018 - Jul 2018(2months)

2 months internship program with Asia General Electric.

#### **Education**

#### **School of Industrial Training and Education**

Advanced Certificate in Industrial Automation, Industrial Automation 2018-2019

Technological University Hmawbi

Bachelor of Engineering, Electronic Engineering 2017-2018

👩 Technological University Hmawbi

Bachelor of Technology, Electronic Engineering 2012-2017

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

ICSI|CNSS Certified Network Security Specialist-

ICSI(InternationalCyberSecurity Institute), UK IssuedMay2020-ExpiresMay2020 17942287

Control Linux for Absolute Beginner - Udemy

UC-3f87f362-ee0d-499b-9c81-0e140cbee3ef

Fundamentals of Python Programming -Símbolo

Oracle Database Foundation – Símbolo

# **Skills**

- Electronic Device Troubleshooting
- Electronic Device Reworking
- Equipment Repair
- Corrective Maintenance
- Preventive Maintenance
- Hardware Support
- Device Testing
- Advanced Soldering
- PCB Reconstruction and Retracing
- Python Programming Language

- Leadership
- Project Management
- Team Work
- Creative Problem Solving
- Critical Thinking
- · Creativity and Innovation
- Microsoft Excel
- Google Sheet
- Online Data Entry
- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft PowerPoint

## Language

Burmese : Fluent

English : Intermediate

Thai : Beginner (Currently Learning)

# **Personal Particulars**

Name	Htet Lwin Kyaw
Gender	Male
Date of Birth	24 September 1994
Race	Burmese
Religion	Buddhist
Nationality	Myanmar
Passport No	MI359705
Marital Status	Single